Guide to the Brooklyn, N.Y., Department of Law, Corporation Counsel records 2013.015
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 1: Case Files, 1849-1920; 98.0 linear feet; in 199 manuscripts boxes, 4 flat boxes and 1 flat file drawer
  - Lane, W. B. - 330 Waverly Ave. health violation, 1908 (Box 186, Folder 12)
  - Roman Catholic Church of the Most Holy Trinity - Petition to close Old Bushwick Road, 1908-1909 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    Includes maps of the property
  - A. C. Schielinger Realty Company - Cancellation of taxes on property in the former Town of New Utrecht, 1909 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    Blocks 6309-6310 and 6322-6323 (Old Ward 30 - Blocks 476-478 and 505-506) (13th Ave., 14th Ave., 83rd St., and 85th St.)
  - Crogan, Thomas G. - Salary lien, 1909 (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - Pearsall, Wright - Last will and testament, 1909 (Box 187, Folder 4)
    Possibly related to water supply property in Rockville Centre
  - Sussman Brothers, 1909 (Box 187, Folder 5)
  - Whalen, John - Water Department civil service dispute, 1909- 1919 (Box 187, Folder 6)
  - Ziegler, August H. - 4 Throop Ave. awning dispute, 1909 (Box 187, Folder 7)
  - Bannon, William D. - Fireman dismissal, 1910 (Box 187, Folder 8)
  - Blum, Benjamin - Hempstead pond contamination (1 of 3), 1910-1912 (Box 187, Folder 9)
    City of New York against Blum
  - Blum, Benjamin - Hempstead pond contamination (2 of 3), 1910- 1912 (Box 187, Folder 10)
  - Blum, Benjamin - Hempstead pond contamination (3 of 3), 1910-1912 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - Butler, James P. - Cashier civil service dispute (1 of 2), 1910 (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - Butler, James P. - Cashier civil service dispute (2 of 2), 1910 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - Dowd, William F. - 9th St. horse death, 1910 (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Guptill, Henry A. - Janitor dismissal, 1910-1911 (Box 188, Folder 5)
  - Hoffman, Maria - Flatbush Ave. sidewalk injury, 1910 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - Long Island Railroad Company - Elimination of grade crossings, 1910 (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - Mann, John W. - Police force dismissal (1 of 2), 1910-1912 (Box 189, Folder 3)
  - Mann, John W. - Police force dismissal (2 of 2), 1910-1912 (Box 189, Folder 4)
  - Murphy, Richard H. - Nurses' Home and Training School contract dispute, 1910-1911 (Box 189, Folder 5)
  - Town of Hempstead - Application of the City of New York to cancel or reduce assessments (1 of 4), 1910-1912 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Town of Hempstead - Application of the City of New York to cancel or reduce assessments (2 of 4), 1910-1912 (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Town of Hempstead - Application of the City of New York to cancel or reduce assessments (3 of 4), 1910-1912 (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Town of Hempstead - Application of the City of New York to cancel or reduce assessments (3 of 4), 1910-1912 (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Walkinshaw, Mary - 4th Ave. sidewalk injury, 1910- 1913 (Box 190, Folder 5)
    Includes plan of sidewalk
  - Byrnes, Frank - 50 Talman St. injury (1 of 3), 1911-1913 (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - Byrnes, Frank - 50 Talman St. injury (2 of 3), 1911- 1913 (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - Byrnes, Frank - 50 Talman St. injury (3 of 3), 1911- 1913 (Box 237, Folder -)
    Survey of Talman St.
  - Hoffman, Charles H. - Clerk salary, 1911-1915 (Box 191, Folder 3)
  - Midwood Athletic Association against Commissioner of Police, 1911 (Box 191, Folder 4)
    Regarding boxing matches; Includes ephemera related to various athletic clubs
  - Moriarty, Annie, as administratrix of Michael Moriarty, 1911 (Box 191, Folder 5)
  - Riggs, George T., 1911 (Box 191, Folder 6)
  - Stackelroth, Frederick - 90 Throop Ave. railroad track injury, 1911 (Box 191, Folder 7)
  - Topping, Charles S. - Glenmore Ave. and Elton St. ambulance accident (1 of 2), 1911-1912 (Box 192, Folder 1)
    City of New York against Topping; Folder (2 of 2) located in oversized box 236
  - Topping, Charles S. - Glenmore Ave. and Elton St. ambulance accident (2 of 2), 1911-1912 (Box 236, Folder -)
    Diagram of the intersection
  - Carleton, Samuel - 514 56th St. sidewalk injury, 1912- 1913 (Box 192, Folder 2)
  - Construction Material and Coal Company - Sewer construction contract dispute, 1912 (Box 192, Folder 3)
  - Dexter, Mary A. - 450 Bay Ridge Ave. injury (1 of 2), 1912-1913 (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Dexter, Mary A. - 450 Bay Ridge Ave. injury (2 of 2), 1912-1913 (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - Duryea, Kate - Assessment dispute, 1912 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    Ward 29 - Block 100 - Lot 67 (Church Ave., between East 7th St. and Bowne St.)
  - Grothe, George against Board of Elections, 1912 (Box 192, Folder 7)
  - McGonigle, Patrick - Strike name from Independence League Party roll, 1912 (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (1 of 6), 1912-1915 (Box 193, Folder 2)
    File (6 of 6) located in Map Room - Flat Maps cabinet; Alabama Ave. and Jamaica Ave.
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (2 of 6), 1912-1915 (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (3 of 6), 1912-1915 (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (4 of 6), 1912-1915 (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (5 of 6), 1912-1915 (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - Nicholson, Eugenie H., administratrix of Charles Nicholson - Wagon accident death (6 of 6), 1912-1915 (Cabinet Map Room - Flat Maps cabinet, Drawer C3)
  - Rosenbach, Emma - 156 Keap St. sidewalk injury (1 of 2), 1912-1915 (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Rosenbach, Emma - 156 Keap St. sidewalk injury (2 of 2), 1912- 1915 (Box 194, Folder 2)
  - Shea, Daniel F. - Tax sale dispute, 1912 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    Woodside, Town of Newtown, Queens
  - Woodruff, Timothy L. and Samuel Greenblatt - Election nomination dispute (1 of 3), 1912 (Box 194, Folder 4)
  - Woodruff, Timothy L. and Samuel Greenblatt - Election nomination dispute (2 of 3), 1912 (Box 194, Folder 5)
  - Woodruff, Timothy L. and Samuel Greenblatt - Election nomination dispute (3 of 3), 1912 (Box 194, Folder 6)
  - Zirinsky, Harry against Ferdinand Richtberg and others - Tax sale dispute, 1912 (Box 195, Folder 1)
    Manhattan Ave. and Meserole St.
  - Ettinger, Virgil P. - 52 South Elliot Pl. sidewalk injury, 1913 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Germania Real Estate and Improvement Company - Purchase of water mains by the City, 1913 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - Harris, David - Recovery of property from police, 1913 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - Hawthorne, George B. - Assistant bookkeeper misconduct, 1913 (Box 195, Folder 5)
  - McClorey, Mary - Wallabout St. injury, 1913 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Radtke, Gustav - Washington Ave. wagon injury, 1913-1915 (Box 195, Folder 7)
  - Barrett Manufacturing Company against Joseph Leopold and others - Paving contract dispute (1 of 2), 1914-1915 (Box 195, Folder 8)
  - Barrett Manufacturing Company against Joseph Leopold and others - Paving contract dispute (2 of 2), 1914-1915 (Box 195, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Children's Aid Society, 1914 (Box 195, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Heights Railroad Company, 1914 (Box 195, Folder 11)
  - Brown, Florence - 899 DeKalb Ave. sidewalk injury (1 of 2), 1914-1915 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Florence - 899 DeKalb Ave. sidewalk injury (2 of 2), 1914-1915 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  - Bruns, Daniel - 883 Manhattan Ave. sidewalk injury, 1914-1915 (Box 196, Folder 3)
  - Butler, John - Coney Island Ave. sidewalk injury, 1914-1915 (Box 196, Folder 4)
    This section of Coney Island Ave. is now known as Prospect Park Southwest; Includes obituary
  - Chrystal, Frances, as administratrix of Eugene F. Chrystal - Kent Ave. trolly car death (1 of 2), 1914 (Box 196, Folder 5)
  - Chrystal, Frances, as administratrix of Eugene F. Chrystal - Kent Ave. trolly car death (2 of 2), 1914 (Box 196, Folder 6)
  - Conran, Joseph F., 1914 (Box 197, Folder 1)
  - Crabbe, Mabel E. - 4th Ave. sidewalk injury (1 of 2), 1914-1916 (Box 197, Folder 2)
    Includes photograph of southeast corner of 44th St. and 4th Ave.
  - Crabbe, Mabel E. - 4th Ave. sidewalk injury (2 of 2), 1914- 1916 (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - Doonan, Edward E., 1914 (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - Lee Avenue Theater Company - 27-31 Lee Ave. building violation, 1914-1915 (Box 197, Folder 5)
    City of New York against Lee Avenue Theater Company
  - Ozone, William and Habeeb - 122 Pacific St. sidewalk injury, 1914-1915 (Box 197, Folder 6)
  - Straus, Julius, 1914 (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Strohsall, Fred - Assessment dispute, 1914 (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Rathgeber, Maria - 136 Willoughby St. condemnation, 1915 (Box 197, Folder 9)
  - Rubenstein, Hyman and Samuel - 111th St. horse injury, 1915-1918 (Box 197, Folder 10)
    Manhattan; Includes blueprint diagram of the street
  - Walsh, M. J. (Deputy Comptroller) against New York Life Insurance and Trust Company - Trust fund dispute, 1915 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Albrecht, William, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Arnold, Bertha, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Aston, Caroline, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - Austin, Philip, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Baker, George B., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Basile, Mary and Charles, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 7)
  - Berry, Elizabeth, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 8)
  - Bihofer, Emil and Francis, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 9)
  - Blair, John F., as administrator of James F. Blair, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - Boyes, Marcia, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 11)
  - Bransfield, Elizabeth, as administratrix, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 12)
  - Brown, Annie, as administratrix, against the Board of Health - Personal injury, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 13)
  - Callahan, Daniel, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 14)
  - Carberry, James, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 15)
  - Chichester, Ezra, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 16)
  - Conlin, Philip J. and Catherine F., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 17)
  - Connelly, Patrick J., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 18)
  - Cunningham, Bridget, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 19)
  - Cunningham, Michael, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 20)
  - Donohue, Mary Jane, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 21)
  - Donovan, Florence F., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 22)
  - Drebinger, William, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 23)
  - England, Elizabeth, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 24)
  - Feo, Dominico, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 25)
  - Fitzgerald, John, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 26)
  - Flanagan, John, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 27)
  - Fliedner, Katie, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 28)
  - Fonde, Lena and Frank, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 29)
  - Gass, Maria Elizabeth, as administratrix, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 30)
  - Harkins, Kate and John, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 31)
  - Hayes, Jerome, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 32)
  - Healey, Peter F., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 33)
  - Henke, Gustave C., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 34)
  - Henry, James P., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 35)
  - Higgins, Michael, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 36)
  - Hilt, Mary, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 37)
  - Hodgkiss, Thomas, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 38)
  - Johnson, Erasmus, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 39)
  - Johnston, Samuel J., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 40)
  - Judge, James F., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 41)
  - Kelly, Patrick, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 42)
  - Kelly, Rose A., as administratrix of Charles F. Kelly, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 43)
  - Kenny, William N., 1918 (Box 198, Folder 44)
  - Knaut, Charlotte, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 45)
  - Koebler, Ellen, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 46)
  - Lawlor, Ann, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 47)
  - Lofquist, Edwin, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 48)
  - Loughlin, Jennie and John, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 49)
  - Lyon, Patrick, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 50)
  - Lyons, Nancy, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 51)
  - Matthews, James, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 52)
  - McCloskey, Mary, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 53)
  - McLaughlin, Edward, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 54)
  - Mehlig, John, 1918 (Box 198, Folder 55)
  - Miller, Mary, as administratrix, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Moran, Annie, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Moran, Elizabeth, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 3)
  - Murraney (?), Martha, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 4)
  - Nielson, George C. F., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 5)
  - O'Hearn, Mary C., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 6)
  - Phillips, Charles S. and others, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 7)
  - Plummer, Charles W., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 8)
  - Porter, Lucy, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 9)
  - Purdy, Andrew B., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 10)
  - Rafalowitz, George, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 11)
  - Reich, John T., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 12)
  - Riker, Abraham, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 13)
  - Ruschman, Anton and Catherine, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 14)
  - Ryan, Lizzie, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 15)
  - Ryan, Sarah, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 16)
  - Seidman, Yette, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 17)
  - Smith, Charles, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Mary T., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 19)
  - Sonnenberger, August, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 20)
  - Stanley, Ann, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 21)
  - Stolpe, Marie, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 22)
  - Sweeney, Patrick, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 23)
  - Urquhart, Allison, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 24)
  - Velansky, Annie, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 25)
  - Weber, Otto, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 26)
  - Williams, Philip T., 1918 (Box 199, Folder 27)
  - Witte, Laura, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 28)
  - Young, Henry, 1918 (Box 199, Folder 29)
  - Bassett, Alexander - Application to prevent naming Joseph De Grace on the Board of Alderman election ballot, 1919 (Box 199, Folder 30)
  - Bernhardt, Jacob - Recovery of property from police, 1919 (Box 199, Folder 31)
  - Bichoniak, Barbara, as surety for Adam Lemansky - Bail remission, 1919-1920 (Box 199, Folder 32)
  - Cunningham, Frank A., as surety of Henry Heedrick - Bail remission, 1919 (Box 199, Folder 33)
    State of New York against Cunningham and Heedrick
  - Battery Park National Bank of New York - Recovery of property from police, 1920 (Box 199, Folder 34)
  - Bernstein, Joseph - Bail remission, 1920 (Box 199, Folder 35)
    State of New York against Joseph Bernstein
- Series 2: Streets, 1844-1912; 22.0 linear feet; in 17 manuscript boxes and 2 flat boxes
  The series is arranged alphanumerically by street name. Numbered streets are expressed numerically (Example: 1st Pl., 7th Ave., 59th St., etc.).
  Folder titles were derived from any original enclosures (typically envelopes or small cartons). Folder titles for loose material were created by the processing archivist following the same format as for the enclosed material. Folder titles typically include both the street name and the relevant boundaries (Example: 11th St., from 2nd Ave. to 8th Ave.).
  The records in the Streets series were found unorganized and are arranged alphanumerically to assist researchers. Please see the Processing Information note for additional general information regarding the arrangement of the series in this collection.
  The Corporation Counsel was responsible for managing the proceedings necessary for the opening, closing, and improving of city streets and the series includes records documenting these activities. The records date from 1844 to 1912 (bulk dates 1850 to 1897) and include reports, lists of expenses, list of property owners, petitions and correspondence from property owners, newspaper notices, and various other supporting documents. Some files include property maps.
  - 2nd St., from 3rd Ave. to 4th Ave., 1870- 1871 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - 3rd St., 1851 (Box 200, Folder 2)
    3rd St. is now known as known as Berry St.
  - 4th Ave., from Flatbush Ave. to City line (near 60th st.) (widening) (1 of 2), 1861- 1867 (Box 200, Folder 3)
  - 4th Ave., from Flatbush Ave. to City line (near 60th st.) (widening) (2 of 2), 1861-1867 (Box 238, Folder -)
    Architectural drawings of the Protestant Episcopal Church of the Redeemer (4th Ave. and Pacific St.)
  - 4th Ave., at Flatbush Ave. (widening), 1881 (Box 200, Folder 4)
    Includes detailed property map
  - 4th St., from North 2nd St. to Bushwick Creek, 1850-1852 (Box 200, Folder 5)
    Includes detailed property map; 4th St. is now part of Bedford Ave., and North 2nd St. is now part of Metropolitan Ave.
  - 4th St., from North 2nd St. to North 13th St., 1859- 1860 (Box 200, Folder 6)
    4th St. is now known as Bedford Ave., and North 2nd St. is now part of Metropolitan Ave.
  - 4th St., 1860s-1870s (Box 200, Folder 7)
    4th St. is now part of Bedford Ave.
  - 4th St., from Grand St. to Division Ave. (widening), 1871 (Box 200, Folder 8)
  - 4th St., from North 13th St. to the intersection of Norman Ave. and Orchard St., 1871 (Box 200, Folder 9)
    4th St. is now part of Bedford Ave. Orchard St. is now part of Manhattan Avenue.
  - 4th St., from northeast terminus to Orchard St., 1872-1877 (Box 200, Folder 10)
  - 5th Ave., from Flatbush Ave. to Atlantic Ave., 1861 (Box 200, Folder 11)
  - 5th Ave., from Atlantic Ave. to Carroll St., and from Atlantic Ave. to Hanson Pl., 1868-1870 (Box 200, Folder 12)
  - 5th Ave., from Wyckoff St. to Warren St. (widening), 1877 (Box 200, Folder 13)
  - 6th Ave., from 39th St. to City line, 1893 (Box 200, Folder 14)
  - 7th Ave., from 1st St. to Green-Wood Cemetery, 1868 (Box 200, Folder 15)
  - 7th Ave., from 39th St. to City line (1 of 2), 1891-1895 (Box 200, Folder 16)
  - 7th Ave., from 39th St. to City line (2 of 2), 1891-1895 (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - 8th Ave., from 20th St. to Green-Wood Cemetery (closing), 1884 (Box 201, Folder 2)
  - 8th Ave., from 39th St. to City line, 1893 (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - 8th St., from 2nd Ave. to Gowanus Canal (closing), 1871 (Box 201, Folder 4)
  - 9th Ave. and 15th St. (widening), 1869 (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - 9th St., from 3rd Ave. to City line, 1863- 1868 (Box 201, Folder 6)
  - 11th St., from 2nd Ave. to 9th Ave., 1868- 1880 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - 11th St. Canal, 1868-1869 (Box 201, Folder 8)
  - 17th St., from 3rd Ave. to high water mark, 1895-1896 (Box 201, Folder 9)
  - 19th St., from 5th Ave. to 9th Ave., 1871 (Box 201, Folder 10)
    9th Ave. is now known as Prospect Park West.
  - 21st St., from 5th Ave. to 6th Ave., circa 1850- 1870 (Box 201, Folder 11)
    List of owners
  - 21st St., from 6th Ave. to City line, 1871 (Box 201, Folder 12)
  - 21st St., from 7th Ave. to City line (closing), 1891 (Box 201, Folder 13)
  - 25th St., 1869 (Box 201, Folder 14)
  - 36th St., from 3rd Ave. to the waterfront (reopen), 1895 (Box 201, Folder 15)
    Petition to reopen a closed portion of 36th St. by property owners
  - 38th St., from 4th Ave. to 5th Ave., 1891 (Box 201, Folder 16)
  - 40th St., from 4th Ave. to 5th Ave., 1891 (Box 201, Folder 17)
  - 41st St., from 3rd Ave. to City line, 1890-1893 (Box 201, Folder 18)
    Includes grading and paving specifications and contract
  - 44th St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893 (Box 201, Folder 19)
  - 45th St. and 46th St., from 2nd Ave. to 3rd Ave., 1895 (Box 201, Folder 20)
  - 47th St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893 (Box 201, Folder 21)
  - 48th St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893 (Box 201, Folder 22)
  - 50th St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893-1894 (Box 201, Folder 23)
  - 51st St., from 4th Ave. to City line, 1891-1894 (Box 201, Folder 24)
  - 52nd St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893 (Box 201, Folder 25)
  - 53rd St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1895 (Box 201, Folder 26)
  - 56th St., from 3rd Ave. to 5th Ave., 1891 (Box 201, Folder 27)
  - 57th St., from 5th Ave. to City line, 1893-1894 (Box 201, Folder 28)
  - 60th St., from 4th Ave. to Gravesend, 1871 (Box 201, Folder 29)
  - 60th St., from 3rd Ave. to Kings Highway, 1897 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  - 62nd St., from 2nd Ave. to 3rd Ave., 1899 (Box 236, Folder -)
    Street opening maps
  - 70th St., from Ovington Ave. to 8th Ave., 1897 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - 71st St., from 6th Ave. to 8th Ave., 1896-1897 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - 75th St., from Fort Hamilton Ave. to 10th Ave., 1896 (Box 202, Folder 4)
  - 75th St., from Shore Rd. to Fort Hamilton Ave. (1 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 202, Folder 5)
    Includes detailed map of Bergen family property
  - 75th St., from Shore Rd. to Fort Hamilton Ave. (2 of 2), 1896-1897 (Box 202, Folder 6)
  - 82nd St., from 4th Ave. to 12th Ave., 1897 (Box 202, Folder 7)
  - 85th St., from 5th Ave. to Fort Hamilton Ave. (closing), 1895 (Box 202, Folder 8)
  - 85th St., 1897 (Box 202, Folder 9)
    Associated Cycling Clubs of Long Island
  - Aberdeen St., from Bushwick Ave. to Broadway, 1888 (Box 202, Folder 10)
  - Aberdeen St., from Bushwick Ave. to Evergreen Cemetery, 1889-1891 (Box 202, Folder 11)
  - Albany Ave., from Herkimer St. to City line, 1868-1873 (Box 202, Folder 12)
  - Ann St., from Broadway to Beaver St., circa 1860s (Box 203, Folder 1)
  - Atlantic Ave., 1854 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Atlantic Ave., from Classon Ave. to City line; and Schuyler St. widening, 1858-1868 (Box 203, Folder 3)
    Includes various railroad companies
  - Atlantic Ave. - Measurements on New Improvement, circa 1860s (Box 203, Folder 4)
  - Atlantic Ave. completion, 1869 (Box 203, Folder 5)
  - Atlantic Ave., from 5th Ave. to Carlton Ave., 1875- 1878 (Box 203, Folder 6)
    Includes Atlantic Avenue Railroad Company of Brooklyn quit-claim deed
  - Atlantic St. Tunnel (closing), 1861 (Box 203, Folder 7)
  - Bainbridge St., from Reid Ave. to Patchen Ave. - German Newspaper Notices, 1875 (Box 203, Folder 8)
    Reid Ave. is now known as Malcolm X Blvd.
  - Banker St., from Calyer St. to the southerly line of the Lewes Thomas farm, 1869 (Box 236, Folder -)
    Assessment map
  - Banker St. and Union Ave., 1869-1873 (Box 203, Folder 9)
  - Banker St., from Franklin Ave. to Union Ave., 1880- 1881 (Box 203, Folder 10)
  - Barbey St., from Sutter Ave. to Livonia Ave., 1892- 1893 (Box 203, Folder 11)
  - Bath Ave., from Bay 19th St. to Bay 35th St., circa 1894 (Box 203, Folder 12)
  - Bay 11th St., from 86th St. to Cropsey Ave., 1896- 1897 (Box 203, Folder 13)
  - Bay 23rd St. (opening) and DeBruyns Lane (closing), 1896- 1898 (Box 203, Folder 14)
    Fragile; Includes notes on contitutional law
  - Bedford Ave., Herkimer St., and Perry Ave., 1871- 1872 (Box 203, Folder 15)
  - Bedford Ave., Herkimer St., and Perry Ave. - Brevoort and D.O. Calkins, 1872-1877 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Bedford Rd. (closing), circa 1867 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Berriman St., from New Lots Rd. to Sutter Ave., 1894 (Box 204, Folder 3)
  - Blake Ave., from Rockaway Ave. to Bristol St. (1 of 2), 1895-1896 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - Blake Ave., from Rockaway Ave. to Bristol St. (2 of 2), 1895-1896 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Blake Ave., from East 98th St. to Fountain Ave., 1900 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Broadway, from Liberty Ave. to City line, 1895-1897 (Box 204, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn, Jamaica, and Flatbush Turnpike Rd., circa 1870s (Box 204, Folder 8)
    Where it intersects Fort Greene Pl.
  - Brooklyn and Jamaica Turnpike Road (Old Plank Road) closing, 1883 -1890 (Box 204, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn and Jamaica Turnpike and Railroad, 1894 (Box 238, Folder -)
    Copies of 1837 maps and documents
  - Broome St., from Graham Ave. to Smith St., 1869 (Box 204, Folder 10)
    Smith Street is now part of Humboldt Street.
  - Bushwick Ave., from Beaver St. to East New York - Objections, 1855-1860 (Box 204, Folder 11)
  - Bushwick Ave. and Morrell St., from North 2nd St. to City line (widening), 1865-1869 (Box 204, Folder 12)
  - Bushwick Ave., from the City line into New Lots, 1869 (Box 204, Folder 13)
  - Bushwick Ave., from Remsen St. to Meserole St., and from Boerum St. to McKibben St. (closing), 1869 (Box 204, Folder 14)
  - Bushwick Ave., from Myrtle Ave. to Wall St. - Closing court yards, 1894-1895 (Box 204, Folder 15)
  - Butler St. or Harrison St., from Columbia St. to the permanent water line, 1859 (Box 238, Folder -)
    Steet opening map
  - Central Ave., Johnson Ave., Knickerbocker Ave., and other streets - Sewer construction, 1869 (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - Central Pl., from Greene Ave. to Grove St., 1874 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Charles Pl., from Broadway to Beaver St., 1868 (Box 205, Folder 3)
    Charles Pl. now known as Sumner Pl.